What's up? Welcome to Models and Agents
for Beginners Episode 26. It's April 30th,
2026. Some awesome AI developments today
sense.
Let's get into it. So imagine your phone
organize your entire
study schedule without you having to
the direction Google
is pushing with its brand new specialized
TPS.
These chips were built specifically for
what people are calling the
agentic era of artificial intelligence.
clever chatbot
and starts acting like a super helpful
you.
Think of a regular computer chip like a
okay? But none
of them amazingly. A TPU is more like a
insanely good at one specific
task which in this case is the kind of
two versions
of this new chip. One version is built for
showing it
tons and tons of examples. The other
the AI once it has
already learned what it needs to know. The
powerful than the
last generation and it moves data from
means the AI is not
sitting around waiting for information. It
automatically spot
when one chip fails in a giant system and
training process
does not crash. What used to take months
researchers try way
more ideas faster. The other chip is
AI's that do not
just answer questions they reason through
things. The new chip
gives the agent three times more internal
thoughts at once.
It also cuts the delay between thoughts by
performance per dollar
spent. That means businesses could help
money. This matters
for you because faster, cheaper, more
homework planning
creative projects or even reminding you
completely natural.
Imagine an AI that does not just suggest a
you outline the
steps find safe materials and schedule
how quickly these
powerful agents will move from big
or on your phone.
It also shows that the hardware underneath
purpose built for
helpful acting AI instead of just smart
related right now for
free. Go to the Gemini website. You may
Google account if
you do not have one. Ask it to plan a fun
materials and a
schedule. Notice how it reasons through
agent thinking
these new chips are designed to make
favorite part of the show
where we go under the hood. Today we are
multiple steps
when it acts like an agent. You know how
party you do not
just blurred out the first idea that pops
need a date that
works for everyone then I need to decide
You hold a few ideas
in your head at once and keep checking
AI agent is doing
when it uses reasoning instead of giving
breaks the task into
smaller thoughts. Keep some of them in its
make sense and
adjusts. Imagine your brain is a
whiteboard so it could
only hold one or two thoughts before it
like handing the AI a
huge whiteboard plus a super fast eraser.
calendar, step two,
compare prices, step three, pick best
three while it works.
The chip also cuts the time it takes to
latency.
So instead of pausing for a few seconds
flows smoothly just
like how you can plan a party in your head
think wait what was I
doing again. And that is basically how
giving the AI more space
to think carefully more speed to move
it does not cost
a fortune to run. So next time you see an
project without
giving up halfway you can tell your
bigger, faster whiteboard
plus really good traffic control for
All right, let us talk
about some other cool stuff happening and
computer. First up
logical data like genes, proteins, and
experts were
completely stuck, Claude solved roughly
It is not just
memorizing facts it is coming up with
questions.
This is exciting because it shows AI is
discovery instead of
just school homework. Future doctors,
use AI as a brainstorming
partner for science projects. You can try
to the Claude
website you may need a parent to help
act like a bioinformatics
researcher here is some simple DNA
copied DNA letters like
ATGC, ATGC. Suggest two interesting things
Watch how it
reasons step by step that is the same
the same style of thinking that helped it tackle the harder biology
problems. It is a fun way to see AI as a
ever wished there was a
way to stop yourself from opening
your homework time.
Someone created a chrome extension called
adorable very determined
fat cat onto your screen whenever you try
timer or blocker
that you can just ignore, this one
will not let you continue
until you deal with it. It is cool because
and visual
instead of stressful. Perfect for students
opening TikTok.
Try it right now. Open chrome on your
Then visit a site you
usually get stuck on like YouTube or
can customize which
sites trigger it a fun zero pressure way
couple quick bits
that caught my eye this week. Open AI
started appearing in
responses from their GPT 5.1 model. It
trait that snuck in during
training and they even used their own
culprit was a nerdy
personality that got a little too
AI companies have to debug
weird little habits in their models. And
robots to work as
baggage handlers. It is a real world
into everyday jobs that
involve physical work in busy changing
the robots you see in
videos might soon be helping you get your
today. Remember every
AI expert started exactly where you are
today made you curious
go try it. That's literally how learning
we'll see you
tomorrow. And if you'd rather watch then
Network links in the
show notes. This podcast is curated by
synthesis of my voice using
11 labs. The primary reason to do this is
consistent with
generating all the content and wanted to
episodes for all
the themes that I enjoy and I hope others
do as well.