Today is April 28th, 2026. Here's your
III
crewed lunar landing slips to know earlier
timeline.
NASA has formally updated the target
landing
under the Artemis program. This adjustment
vehicle testing
and address integration challenges ahead
surface.
The delay reflects the realities of
safety and reliability
must come first. Vehicle integration has
anticipated,
yet this mission remains the cornerstone
for returning humans to the lunar surface.
I appreciate how the agency is choosing a
forward.
While we wait a little longer for boots
some very
personal questions about what
next generation of
explorers. Ongoing studies are examining
and other
spaceflight stressors could affect
everything from cellular
changes to how the body manages hormones
direct implications for
future lunar bases and crewed trips to
children
off Earth. Understanding these effects
space missions
sustainable. It is a reminder that
most fundamental
aspects of being human. Speaking of future
rapidly expanding
its satellite fleet to bring broadband to
launch alliance
Atlas V rocket successfully delivered a
record tying heavy payload of 29 project
internet satellites from Florida. The
Amazon's low-Earth
orbit constellation to provide global
existing payload record
and shows the Atlas V still delivers
vehicles come online,
the rocket continues to prove its heavy
brings the
constellation closer to connecting remote
watch commercial
space move at this pace. While Amazon
continues pushing
the frontier of full reusability with its
rolled out a next
generation starship vehicle booster
program now marks three
years since its first flight. Engineers
that treats every
ground test as close to flight conditions
rapid
reusability for deep space missions.
suggests they are
closing in on the reliability needed for
iteration feels
like witnessing a genuine engineering
Earth orbit,
a quiet but vital Russian cargo delivery
Station.
The uncrewed Russian Progress 95
port of the Zvezda
module. It launched two days earlier from
essentials for
the station crew. This resupply mission
the station crew. This resupply mission ensures continued smooth operations aboard the orbiting laboratory.
Regular cargo runs like this keep the crew
without interruption.
In the background of flashy new rockets,
long-term human space
flight possible. They remind us that
logistical support.
While the station keeps humming along,
statements about America's
lunar timeline. The head of NASA expressed
land
astronauts on the moon ahead of any
as the agency balances
international partnerships with domestic
confidence reflects a
clear focus on maintaining the United
same time,
lawmakers continue to scrutinize budgets
delicate dance between
ambition and practical realities. That
when NASA's administrator
nominee spent two days testifying on
nominee spent two days testifying on Capitol Hill. The NASA administrator nominee appeared on Capitol
Hill to discuss reduced funding proposals,
commercialization of
space activities. Jared Isaacman defended
accelerated exploration.
Lawmakers raised concerns about potential
program cancellations during the hearings.
The back-and-forth highlighted how policy
the pace of our return to the moon.
It was interesting to see a nominee with
these questions
directly. These conversations will likely
influence priorities for years to come.
Now, here's something that blew my mind
model suggests energy
from decaying dark matter could have
formation of supermassive
black holes. If you compressed all the
volume the size of our
solar system, its total mass would still
five. Streams of
energetic particles would pour into the
compressing the
gas clouds that would otherwise take far
alongside one of those decay
products, racing at nearly the speed of
it could dump
enough energy to trigger runaway accretion
letting them
balloon to millions of solar masses while
years old.
The mechanism relies on a specific decay
some proposed dark
matter candidates. That neatly matches the
sees these
unexpectedly massive objects already in
particle properties
that would produce exactly the right
cosmological signals
we already trust. We can model the
but nobody yet knows whether
this exotic decay truly happened, or if we
of the puzzle.
That same telescope is also showing us how
even with the most
powerful instrument we have ever launched.
Telescope to study
promising exo-moon candidates around a
hoping to find an
earth moon analog. The host star's
from potential moons.
This illustrates the extreme challenges of
distant worlds,
even cutting edge instruments face limits
clues we seek.
It is a humbling reminder of how much
the existence of
exo-moons. Closer to home, our Mars rovers
that could rewrite
parts of the red planet's story. The
and identified seven
previously unseen organic molecules. This
so far in a
single sample. Curiosity drilled into the
laboratory
detected these distinct organic molecules
planet.
The molecules survived billions of years
adds to the
growing inventory of complex carbon
our understanding of
its past habitability and paints a richer
existed when water
once flowed across the surface. Each new
environmental
conditions that might once have supported
to climb through
layered sediments that record millions of
outcrop.
What would it mean for our search for
have a non-biological
origin we have not imagined yet? While
Martian rocks,
NASA's orbital eyes just captured a
on Earth.
NASA's Earth Observatory released a
red and orange
beach forests across southern Patagonia.
autumn at its peak.
It highlights seasonal changes on our own
remote sensing reveals
dynamic ecosystems. Seeing Earth from
beautiful perspective.
The fiery colors look almost otherworldly,
beneath our feet.
That same sense of wonder is alive and
continue to produce
stunning images with surprisingly modest
smartphone and digital
single lens reflex captures of the Orion
modest backyard
telescopes and careful processing to
demonstrate how accessible
equipment combined with patients can still
is genuinely
inspiring to see what dedicated amateurs
images connect all
of us to the cosmos without needing
keep an eye on how the
Artemis timeline adjustments and the
shape the next round
of lunar mission contracts. That covers
with a fellow
space enthusiast if you found it
you found it interesting. I'm Patrick in Vancouver. See you tomorrow.
This podcast is curated by Patrick but
voice synthesis of my voice using 11 labs.
The primary reason to do this is I
consistent with generating
all the content and wanted to focus on
for all the themes that
I enjoy and I hope others do as well.