Hey, welcome to Fascinating Frontiers
Episode 60.
Today is April 30th, 2026.
Let's look at what's new across the
frontiers
of space and science.
A Falcon Heavy is rolling toward the pad
for its first launch in 18 months
while Europe prepares Ariane Six's second
flight
with four boosters.
Space X just completed back-to-back
launches
of a Falcon Heavy and a Falcon 9.
Both side boosters from the heavy came
back to Earth
and landed safely at landing zones 2 and
40.
This marks the vehicle's return after a
year and a half hiatus.
The successful landings prove
that rapid reusability still works
even for these heavy lift missions.
From an engineering perspective,
it is impressive to see the same hardware
fly
again so reliably after that long gap.
The precision required to bring those
boosters
down on target speaks to how mature
the recovery systems have become.
Now while the heavy was making headlines
on the East Coast, another Falcon 9 was
busy
expanding the biggest satellite
constellation on the planet.
A Falcon 9 launched from California
and successfully deployed its full
complement
of 24 Starlink satellites into orbit.
This keeps the constellation growing at a
steady pace.
It also demonstrates the reliability of
the workhorse rocket
on dedicated rideshare class missions.
You can see how space X has turned this
vehicle
into a true utility player that can handle
both crude flights and these smaller
dedicated launches.
Every new batch like this one strengthens
the network
that so many people now rely on for
internet access
from almost anywhere on earth.
Speaking of things headed toward the moon,
one piece of space X hardware has an
unusual destination
coming up in a few months.
You know what is fascinating about this?
An expended Falcon 9 upper stage is now on
a trajectory
that will cause it to strike the moon in
August.
The deliberate crash will happen
at roughly 2.5 kilometers per second.
That impact will release energy equivalent
to a few hundred kilograms of TNT
and send pressure waves rippling through
solid rock.
Size monitors placed by earlier landers
will detect those waves from hundreds of
kilometers away.
Because we know the exact mass, speed and
impact angle,
the event becomes a precisely calibrated
probe
of the moon's crust and mantle.
The really wild part is that the moon
rings like a bell
for up to an hour after even a modest
strike.
It reveals layering we still do not fully
understand.
We can watch the flash from orbit measure
the seismic
Coda from the surface and compare both to
computer models.
Yet one specific mystery refuses to yield.
Why do some lunar impact sites show
unexpectedly deep fracturing
while others appear to heal far faster
than rock physics predicts?
That single unanswered detail
sits at the heart of how the moon's
interior
has evolved over billions of years.
From an artificial impact on the moon
to a very real new rocket preparing to
leave Earth Europe
is about to fly its most powerful launcher
again.
Europe's most powerful rocket, Ariane VI,
is set for its second flight with four
solid boosters.
The launch is scheduled between 9.08 a.m.
and 9.57 a.m.
British summertime on April 30th, 2026.
This mission continues the launchers early
operational campaign.
It also expands Europe's independent heavy
lift capability
at a time when reliable access to space
matters more than ever.
Having a homegrown heavy rocket
that can fly on its own schedule
strengthens the continent's position
in the growing international space
economy.
While new rockets grab the spotlight of
veteran astronaut
with a unique medical background
is getting ready for his first trip to
orbit.
A Neil Menon, a former SpaceX flight
surgeon
and member of NASA's 2021 astronaut class
will make his first trip to space.
His mission launches on July 14th.
He will head to the International Space
Station.
His background in aerospace medicine
brings unique operational insight
to long duration expeditions.
Having a doctor astronaut who already
understands
the spacecraft systems from the operator
side
should prove valuable during what could be
an extended stay.
It is always reassuring when the crew
includes someone
who has lived and breathed the medical
side
of human spaceflight for years.
From the human side of spaceflight,
let us swing over to what you can actually
see
with your own eyes this month.
This month, the big and little dippers are
riding high
in the northern evening sky.
All five bright planets are visible right
now.
The ETA Aquariod meteors from Halle's
comet
are also active.
Sky and telescope has put together a
complete backyard guide
that helps observers make the most of
these sites.
Even if you only have a few minutes after
dark,
you can step outside, spot the dippers,
trace the planets
and maybe catch a meteor or two.
It is a great time to reconnect with the
sky
without any special equipment.
While we are looking up powerful
telescopes
are still revealing distant galaxies.
NASA's Hubble Space Telescope
imaged the luminous barred spiral galaxy
IC 486.
The image was captured on April 13th,
2026.
It reveals the galaxy's soft glow against
the blackness of space.
You can clearly see the graceful spiral
arms
and the stellar populations that trace
them.
It is a classic example of the structures
that build the universe we see today.
Every new Hubble portrait like this one
reminds me how beautiful and orderly
spiral galaxies can look from millions of
light years away.
From galaxies millions of light years
away,
we come back to our own cosmic
neighborhood
and a dramatic event from 1,000 years ago.
On April 30th, 10-6, the brightest
supernova
in recorded human history flared in the
constellation Lupus.
It reached 16 times the brightness of
Venus.
The event was visible across China, Japan,
the Middle East, and Europe.
It was reportedly bright enough to read by
at night.
Some researchers think it may even appear
in North American rock art.
That supernova was a reminder of how
dynamic the cosmos can be
and how profoundly those events must have
affected people
who witnessed them without any modern
context.
While lawmakers debate future rockets,
the current Artemis crew recently received
some high-profile encouragement.
President Trump welcomed the Artemis II
crew to the White House.
The event celebrated the upcoming crewed
lunar fly-by mission.
It underscored continued high-level
political support
for NASA's return to the moon.
Seeing the crew recognized at that level
helps keep public attention focused on the
mission
that will send humans beyond lower orbit
for the first time in decades.
Political support is important,
but so is the technology that will let
future explorers
survive on the lunar surface.
Engineers have created hair-thin nanotube
shielding
that can be 3D printed directly
onto electronics and solar panels.
Picture a fleet of autonomous rovers
trundling across the lunar South Pole,
three kilometers from base
when a solar storm alert suddenly lights
up mission control.
Instead of scrambling to retrieve them,
engineers can simply rely on these
lightweight layers.
The shielding adds almost no mass,
yet it is flexible enough to survive
the extreme temperature swings and
vibration of launch.
Early tests suggest it can deflect
the worst of the high-energy particles
that would otherwise fry unshielded
systems.
What comes next is flight qualification
on actual lunar hardware.
That could open the door to long-duration
robotic missions
in permanently shadowed regions.
One question remains,
how will these nanotube layers hold up
after years of micrometeorite sandblasting
and relentless UV exposure on the moon?
Protecting hardware is one thing.
Sometimes you have to cancel hardware
entirely.
The Canadian Space Agency terminated last
year's contract
with Spire Global to build a fleet
of small satellites dedicated to
monitoring wildfires.
The decision ends one planned contribution
to Canada's Earth observation
capabilities.
It is never easy to cancel a project,
especially one aimed at something
as important as wildfire tracking.
Still, these kinds of adjustments happen
as budgets and priorities shift
across government space programs.
On a brighter note, new materials and
clever ideas
are still moving forward at NASA.
Al Nash from the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
spoke on moving interesting ideas
to selected astra studies.
The seminar took place on April 30th.
It explored considerations
for advancing early stage astrophysics
technology concepts.
Hearing how JPL thinks about turning
promising ideas
into funded studies gives a glimpse
into the careful filtering process
that shapes future missions.
While we push new tech Earth itself,
keeps putting on quite a show.
As winter gave way to spring,
distinct cloud patterns formed textbook
examples
of various atmospheric phenomena over the
Gulf of Alaska.
Satellite imagery captured the transition
and the dynamic weather system shaping
Earth's
high latitude skies.
The images are a beautiful reminder that
even from orbit,
our own planet can look every bit
as dramatic as anything we see in deep
space.
Before we go, keep an eye on how that
upcoming lunar impact
in August unfolds, because the seismic
data could reshape
what we think we know about the Moon's
interior.
That covers today's space and science
news.
Share this with a fellow space enthusiast
if you found it interesting.
I'm Patrick and Vancouver, see you
tomorrow.
And if you'd rather watch than listen,
find us on YouTube at NARA Network, links
in the show notes.
This podcast is curated by Patrick,
but generated using AI voice synthesis
of my voice using 11 labs.
The primary reason to do this is
I unfortunately don't have the time to be
consistent
with generating all the content
and wanted to focus on creating consistent
and regular episodes for all the themes
that I enjoy
and I hope others do as well.