It's a new day on Tesla Short's Time
Daily, episode 453 for April 28, 2026.
I'm Patrick coming to you from Vancouver.
Let's get into what's moving in the Tesla
world today.
Tesla is hiring engineers to build a
wireless battery management system for
CyberCab that removes heavy wiring
harnesses across its vehicles.
Tesla is actively recruiting a staff
electrical design engineer to develop
wireless battery management systems
specifically for the CyberCab and
next generation battery electronics.
The goal is to replace heavy copper wiring
harnesses with small radio
frequency chips on each module.
This simplifies automated assembly because
robots would no longer need to
route and connect complex wire bundles.
It cuts weight, which improves efficiency
and range,
while also reducing vibration-related
failure points over hundreds of
thousands of kilometers.
Recycling becomes easier too since there
is less copper to separate at
end of life.
The plan is to spread this approach across
everything Tesla builds which
represents a meaningful shift in how
start.
What stands out to me is how this targets
manufacturing friction at its source
rather than just tweaking existing
designs.
This one actually lines up perfectly with
the deeper first
principles piece we are doing this week,
so let us jump straight into that.
Most people still imagine battery packs as
complicated
labor-intensive bundles of copper wiring.
But the physics shows those harnesses are
mostly dead weight and
manufacturing friction once you have
reliable wireless data transfer.
Removing them frees up space for more
range.
It also eliminates vibration-failure
points that accumulate over long distances
and thermal cycles.
This lets robots simply drop modules in
place during assembly
which could dramatically change production
speed and cost.
If it delivers even half the expected
gains,
this quiet change could shift the cost
structure enough
to make lower price electric vehicles
truly viable at volume.
It becomes a foundational move that
robots.
Tesla tends to attack problems by
with real fleet data.
Starting with the cybercab and
clean sheet
to prove the architecture first.
They have taken similar approaches before
with structural battery packs
accepting early challenges for long-term
advantage.
All right, let us come back down to Earth
out to
cars on the road right now.
The FSD version 14 update has begun
deploying to early vehicles.
Owners are already sharing screenshots of
the download and progress.
Tesla added navigation as a specific
other category.
This change came after owners requested
better ways to report issues.
These small practical adjustments show the
team iterating quickly on the software.
They also demonstrate that the engineers
actually
use the reporting tools.
Better data categorization should help the
time.
It is a good example of the product
feedback loop working in real time.
And the early feedback from someone who
just tried it for the first time
is genuinely worth hearing.
A South Korean reporter tried FSD
came away impressed.
The car handled traffic lights merging
intervention needed.
It smoothly navigated around a parked
truck and stopped precisely at crosswalks.
The reporter noted it felt more rule
same conditions.
This kind of real world validation matters
South Korea.
It builds confidence in supervised
quite different
from North America. Stories like this help
about the technology.
That kind of buzz is helpful because Tesla
same
Korean market. Tesla Korea is offering its
Model Y
rear wheel drive. This applies in areas
dried up.
The Model Y remains the top selling import
willing to spend
its own money to keep sales momentum
Tesla is stepping in
directly to support buyers. This market
business environment
can vary sharply by region. While we are
data just gave the
cyber cab another quiet win. Real world
only 1.75 passengers.
This lines up well with the cyber cab as
undercuts the
loud criticism that a robot taxi needs
majority of trips,
the simpler vehicle appears sufficient.
the simpler vehicle appears sufficient. This data point strengthens the case for the cyber
cab as focused approach to robot taxi
have been repeated
without much real world backing. If you
in person,
Tesla is bringing the future to Miami this
at
Lumis Park during the Miami Grand Prix fan
able to see
the cyber cab up close. They can meet
These hands-on events
matter because experiencing the vision
interaction helps people
form their own opinions about the
way to engage potential
customers and curious observers in a high
fun side,
Tesla just dropped a pretty cool
the classic
talking car kitty experience using FSD and
natural
conversation while driving. It responds in
personality-driven.
This is a nice reminder that the existing
fleet can unlock new personality features.
Owners do not need to wait for future
out.
It shows how software can continue to add
delight to vehicles already on the road.
Before we wrap a couple of quick hits are
half-century-old
Chevrolet beat a cyber truck in a straight
rounds.
It is feeding the two heavy narrative even
truck as a pure
drag racer. The result has sparked plenty
and power
delivery. These viral moments shape public
focused on
efficiency, real-world utility, and
bragging rights.
The company will likely keep refining
makes sense.
On a more practical note for owners, Tesla
on new
vehicles. Fix auto has also gained
which expands the certified
network. That should help reduce weight
times as the fleet keeps growing.
That's your Tesla news for today. TSLA
closed at $378.67 up 80.0.2%.
If you found this useful, a rating or
helps new listeners
find the show. You can also find us on
Vancouver. Thanks
for listening and I will see you tomorrow.
generated using
AI voice synthesis of my voice using 11
unfortunately don't
have the time to be consistent with
focus on creating
consistent and regular episodes for all
do as well.